Jordi Burgos López

Senior Software Engineer

⊠ jordiburgos@gmail.com

I am a passionate software developer. Regularly, I enjoy attending conferences and meetups to keep me up to date. Besides, I like to develop personal projects to improve my knowledge. I like to work with people, I am nice and easy to work with. In addition I have experience training and mentoring team members.

Experience

2019-Present Lead Software Development Engineer, Mastercard, Dublin, Ireland.

Multinational Company; 18.600 employees; Financial Services, Technology.

- o Event Framework: Research and Development to enable building applications using event driven architecture. Java, Spring Boot, Spring Integration.
 - Design architecture and implement a Spring Boot library to enable event driven applications with several brokers (Kafka, NATS, Azure Service Bus) and cloud providers.
 - Design and implement a Maven archetype generator for event driven applications and configuration.
 - Investigate usage of project definition specifications like AsyncAPI.
- o Service design bootstraping: Research and Development to enable Mastercard developers with pre-designed project templates.
 - Design project strategy, project architecture and implementation details.
- Next Edge: Research and Development of the next generation of Mastercard payment network.
 - Engage with stakeholders (Enterprise Architecture, Shared Services and Security) to drive and understand implications for the new network.
 - Investigate and implement several POC with Kafka, NATS, Azure Service Bus and Spring Boot.

2016–2019 **Senior Software Engineer**, *SAP*, Dublin, Ireland.

Multinational Company; 85.000 employees; Business Operations and Customer Relations.

- o SAP Analytics Cloud: Collect and produce statistics for dataset fields and metadata search. Java, Spring, JMS, REST, SAP HANA SQL.
 - Design and implement service architecture using Spring and JMS.
 - Design database structure and analysis SQL queries.
 - Implement service to support several cloud providers.
- o Predictive Analytics: Software to create Machine Learning and Big Data processing pipelines graphically. Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Webpack, SAP HANA database, SAP UI5.
 - Design and implement user interface architecture using TypeScript, Webpack and SAP UI5.
 - Train and supervise junior developers in the team.
 - Investigate and resolve bugs from server side code base.

2014–2016 Senior Software Engineer, IBM, Dublin, Ireland.

Multinational Company; 400.000 employees; IT consulting.

- HR suite project: Software suite for HR related applications. Java, REST, JPA, JAX-RS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, IBM WebSphere, Linux.
 - Design and implement architecture of back-end REST services with JAX-RS and JPA on WebSphere.
 - Design and implement AngularJS User Interface connected to the REST back-end.
 - Collaborate with User Experience (UX) team on the design of interface.
 - Work using Agile, Design Thinking and Test Driven Development methodology.

2006–2014 Java Software Engineer, GFT IT Consulting, S.L.U., Valencia, Spain.

Multinational Company; 4.800 employees; IT and Services industry.

- o Global Funds Derivatives Tracker: Capture fund derivatives business at Deutsche Bank. It is a repository of core funds, market data and derivatives. Java, Spring, Hibernate, Oracle PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, JS, ExtJS, Linux.
 - Create reusable components and code to increase developers performance.
 - Optimize the application at all layers. Provide technical support to team members.
- Feed Consolidation Layer: ETL project to fetch data from several sources in proprietary formats into a unified data representation. Java, Oracle PL/SQL, OpenAdaptor, Maven, Teamcity, Linux.
 - Improve feed processing performance to increase message volume with the same infrastructure.
 - Analyse, improve and implement the Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC), CI and CD.
- Legal Vehicle Database: Track legal entity population for tax reporting purposes at Deutsche Bank. Java, GWT, Hibernate, Oracle.
 - Rewrite the user interface of an inherited project using Google Web Toolkit (GWT).

2001–2005 **Java Developer**, *Infoquip S.L.*, Valencia, Spain.

Local company; 5 employees; Computer material store and custom software development.

- Java Program Generator: Java application generator to cut delivery times. Java, Swing, JDBC, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Linux.
 - Design and develop the engine for code generation with SQL database storage.
 - Develop a report generator, with viewer and printer.
- Sales point program for furniture company. Java, Swing, JDBC, MySQL.
 - Sales program for interconnected stores.
 - Take client requirements and develop application using generator.

1999–2000 **Technical School internship**, *Infoquip S.L.*, Valencia, Spain.

Local company; 5 employees; Computer material store and custom software development. **Internship**, 250 Hours.

Learn Java programming language. Build and configure PCs and networks.

Professional certification

Jun-2018 D	eep Learning	and Neural	Networks	Specialization	on Coursera
------------	--------------	------------	----------	----------------	-------------

Sep-2016 Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera

Apr-2013 MongoDB for Java Developers

M101J

Jul-2012 Object Oriented Analysis and Design with UML

Mar-2011 Oracle PL/SQL Developer Certified Associate

OCA PL/SQL

Jan-2009 Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform SE 6

SCJP 6.0

Education

2004–2007 Master of Computer Science, Universidad Politécnica, Valencia, Spain.

2005 **ERASMUS grant**, *University College of Engineering*, Odense, Denmark.

2000–2004 Bachelor of Computer Science, Universidad Politécnica, Valencia, Spain.

1997–2000 Technical School Management Information Systems, I.E.S. El Cabañal, Valencia, Spain.

1996–1997 **Technical School Administrative Assistant**, *I.F.P. La Marxadella*, Torrente, Spain.

1995 Primary School Graduated, C.P. Ausia's March, Picaña, Spain.

Languages

English First Certificate English (FCE)

Level B2 CEFR, Jul-2012

Spanish Native Catalan Native

Skills

Languages Java (J2SE, J2EE), JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Shell, scripting languages

Web REST, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React, AngularJS, SAP UI5

Frameworks Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Integration, JPA, Hibernate

OS Linux, Windows, Docker

Databases Oracle SQL and PL/SQL, MySQL, SAP HANA

Message Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS

brokers

Testing Unit Testing, Integration Testing, JUnit, Mockito, Selenium, Karma, Mocha

Methodology Agile software development, Scrum, Test Driven Development (TDD)

Web servers Apache Tomcat, WebSphere, Jetty

Build tools Maven, Gradle, Ant, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp

Cl Jenkins, Teamcity

Version Git, Subversion (SVN), CVS

control